well good afternoon everybody welcome
还有，大家下午好欢迎
good to see you today we're going to
很高兴见到你今天 我们要
continue our study of exceptional
继续我们的卓越研究
control flow by looking at some higher
通过看一些上级控制流程
level mechanisms known as Linux signals
称为 Linux信号 电平的机制
and see non-local jumps now we're going
看看非本地的跳跃，现在我们要去
to spend most of our most of our time
花大部分的我们这个时代最
looking at signals because they have a
看着 信号，因为他们 有一个
lot of subtleties the semantics can be
很多微妙的语义 可以
kind of confusing so we're going to
那种混乱，所以我们打算
we're going to spend most of our time
我们将 花更多的时间
there and I'll mention the idea of
那里，我会提到的想法
non-local jumps but for details on those
非本地的跳跃，但对那些细节
you'll want to look in your textbook and
你想在你的教科书的外观 和
in the slides at the Supplemental slides
在补充幻灯片幻灯片
at the end of this the slide deck now to
在此滑动台的现在到端
motivate the notion of signals I want to
激励我要的信号概念
want to talk a little bit about shell
想谈谈 外壳 一点点
programs now as we mentioned last time
现在的方案，因为我们上次 提到 的
there's only one way to create
只有一种创建方式
prophecies on a Linux system and that's
在Linux系统上的预言，这就是
using the for call in fact the all of
使用用于实际上所有 的 呼叫
the processes on the system actually
系统上的过程实际
form a hierarchy so that the very first
形成了一个等级 ， 使得 第一个
process created when you boot the system
当流程引导 系统创建
up is the anit process which has the
向上是 ANIT方法，该方法具有
process ID of one and then all of the
一个，然后将所有的的进程ID
processes on the system are descendants
该系统上的进程是后代
of that of that init process
那是init进程的
now the anit process of when it starts
现在它开始时的过程ANIT
up it creates demons which are
多达它创建魔所为
long-running programs that provide
长时间运行的程序，提供
services typically so for example a web
通常这样例如Web服务
server and other kinds of services that
服务器和其他类型的服务， 这些 服务
you always want running on the system
你总是希望在系统上运行
and then eventually it creates login so
然后最终它创建登录，这样
called logging shells which provide the
所谓的记录炮弹其提供
command line interface to to users so
命令行界面给用户，以便
when you log in to a Linux system what
当您登录到Linux系统是什么
you eventually get to is a login shell
你最终得到一个登录shell
that's expecting you to type commands
该公司预计，您可以键入命令
now the login login shelves execute
现在登录登录货架 执行
programs on your your behalf so when we
代表你对你的程序，所以当我们
type something into the shell say we
输入一些东西到外壳说，我们
type the LS command we're asking we're
输入ls命令我们要求 我们
asking the shell to run the executable
问外壳运行可执行文件
program called LS and so what the shell
程序调用LS还等什么壳
will do is it will create a child and
需要做的是它会创建一个孩子，
then it will execute LS within that
然后它会执行内 的 LS
child process and it's possible that
孩子的过程，它可能是
that process may create other other
这个过程可能会产生其他其他
child processes so a shell is an
子流程，使一个shell就是一个
application program no different from
应用程序没有什么不同
any other program that executes programs
任何其他程序 ，执行程序
on the behalf of users okay the the
对用户的名义行不行的
default shell for Linux is called bash
为Linux默认的shell被称为bash的
but there's a there's other shells that
但有一个还有 其他炮弹
that were created done earlier with
已创建与前面做
earlier versions of Unix
早期版本的Unix
SH was the original shell called the
SH是原壳名为
bourne shell because it was created by
Bourne shell的，因为它是由创建
steven born and when berkeley came out
史蒂芬出生在伯克利出来
with their distribution of unix they
与他们的UNIX，他们的分布
created a shell called CSH now the the
创建了一个名为CSH现在壳
execution in a shell is a sequence of
执行在一个壳的序列
read and evaluate steps so first a shell
读取和评估步骤，使第一壳
prints out a prompt and then it waits
打印出一个提示，然后它等待
for it waits for you to type something
它等待你输入一些东西
in on the command line and hit return
在命令行和回车上
okay and typically what you're what
没关系，通常 你是 什么 什么
you're typing in is a is a command which
你键入是一个命令，
is just the so the first thing you type
只是这样你输入的第一件事
is a command and then you follow that
是一个命令，然后您按照
with optional arguments separated by
与 由分离 的可选参数
spaces okay so once you hit once you
空间好了，一旦你打你一次
type in a command and those optional
键入一个命令和那些任选
arguments and hit return the shell
参数并回车 壳
checks for the end of file character
检查文件字符的结束
which is a control D to terminal and if
这是一种控制D钮 终端，并且如果
so it exits otherwise it evaluates that
所以它退出，否则它是评估
command line and the evaluation consists
命令行和评估包括
and then when it returns from the
然后当它从返回
evaluation it just does the same thing
评价它只是做同样的 事情
over it
在它
now the evaluation consists of the
现在评估包括的
following kinds of steps first it parses
第一下列各种步骤它解析
the command line and by and and in the
在命令行，并通过和，并在
process so it takes the command line
过程因此需要在命令行
which in this example is in buff and it
在该示例中是在浅黄色和它
produces an RV array okay where arc v-0
产生一个RV阵列没关系其中 弧V-0
is a command and then RV one and two and
是一个命令然后RV一个和两个与
so on are the optional arguments and the
等都是可选的参数和
convention in the shell is that if the
公约中的外壳是 ，如果
command line is terminated by an
命令行是通过一个终止
ampersand then you're asking the shell
符号然后你 问壳
to run that job to run that command in
运行该作业在运行该命令
the background meaning the shell won't
背景意味着外壳不会
wait for that job to finish before it
等待工作之前它完成
goes through its next read step if you
经过它的下一个读一步，如果你
if the the line that you type doesn't
如果您键入的行 不
have an ampersand then you're asking the
有一个连字符，然后你问
shell to to run that job in the
壳牌运行 在 该 作业
foreground which means the shell will
前景，这意味着罩体的意志
wait so so first we parse this this
等了这么所以首先我们分析这个 这个
command line into an art V array and we
命令行为艺术 V阵列和我们
return whether or not it was terminated
返回它是否被终止
by an ampersand B so B GG for background
通过一个与符号乙所以 B GG背景
if art V zero is null then that means we
如果本领域V零是 空值，则这意味着我们
just hit we just hit return right so as
刚打我们只是打回右 从而
an empty line so we'll just return and
一个空行，所以我们只返回和
just ignore those now a shell also
不理会那些现在还壳
implements the what are called built-in
实现了所谓的内置
commands so various things like jobs b g
命令使各种事物一样工作BG
FG are examples of built-in commands
FG是内置命令的例子
which are just implemented in the shell
这是在刚刚壳实现
itself so if you type if the first thing
本身，所以如果你在输入时的第一件事
you type if the command you enter is a
您键入如果 您输入 的 命令 是
built-in then the shell will it will
内置那么shell将它
check that it will check Arg be 0 for a
检查 将 检查 精氨酸 为 0
to see if it's a built-in command and if
看它是否是一个内置的命令，并且
it is it'll just execute it whatever
这是它只会 执行它什么
whatever it is you asked it to do okay
无论是你要求它做的 好
otherwise if it's not a built-in then
否则，如果它不是一个内置的再
that means that that you're asking the
这意味着，你问了
shell to run some program okay
外壳运行一些程序好吗
so in that case the shell will fork a
所以在这种情况下，外壳将叉一个
child and then the child's will execute
孩子，那么孩子的将执行
that program by calling exact ve passing
该程序 通过 调用 准确 传递已经
is the first argument the name of the
是第一个参数的名称
command and as the second and third
命令和作为第二和第三
arguments are V and the environment
参数是V和环境
respectively
分别
now exact the e if you recall from last
现在确切的e。如果从去年召回
time never returns unless there's an
时间永远不会返回，除非有一个
error so it checks so we check it the
错误，因此会检查 ，所以我们检查了
return value for x XE e and if it
对于x XE e 和如果 返回值
returns less than zero
返回小于 零
in fact the only time it will return if
事实上唯一的一次将 返回如果
it does return it will always return
它返回它总是返回
minus one but we're just being careful
减人，但我们只是要小心
here so we check that for a an error and
在这里，所以我们检查 了一个错误，
in print and error message if we find an
在印刷 和 错误信息，如果我们找到一个
error and then exit so once the once the
错误，然后退出 所以一旦一次
once the parent gets control again then
一旦父母再次得到控制权，然后
it waits for that foreground job to
它等待前台作业
terminate okay so if it's not a
终止没关系，所以如果它不是一个
background job then it waits for it to
后台作业然后等待其
terminate by calling lakebed and waiting
通过调用湖底和等待终止
for that child that foreground job to
对于孩子说前台作业
terminate and then and reaping it
终止，然后和它收获
otherwise if it's a background job it
否则，如果它是一个后台 作业它
just prints a a message and goes on so
只是打印 AA消息并继续如此
this is really interesting right that
这真的很 有趣正确的
there's really the only difference
没什么，唯一的区别
between a foreground job and a
前台工作和之间
background job is just that the shell
后台作业 仅仅是外壳
does await it on that job or not right
并等待它的是工作或不对 的
so there otherwise there's really
所以否则真的
there's really no difference now what's
真的没有区别 ，现在什么
the prob there's a problem with our
的概率有一个问题我们
example shell and that the problem is
例如壳 ，而这个问题是
that we're we're doing the right thing
我们正在我们正在做正确的事
for the foreground job we always have to
对于前台 工作，我们总是要
reap these children so they so that
获得这些孩子，让他们使
there's their state can be released but
那里是他们的状态能够被释放，但
we're not we're not doing anything to
我们不是，我们没有做任何事情
reap any background jobs right when if
获得任何后台工作 的权利，如果当
the background job so if not BG we're
后台工作，所以如果不是 BG我们
just printing a message and then we're
只是打印一条 消息， 然后我们
returning and then we're continuing with
返回，然后我们在继续
this read evaluate step and never never
这个阅读评估步骤，并且从来就不曾
going back and and taking care of that
回去和和采取的是照顾
of that background job so this is a
这样的 背景下工作 的 ，所以这 是一个
problem because that background job will
问题的原因 是 后台作业会
eventually become if we have enough of
最终成为，如果我们有足够的
those jobs we create a memory leak that
这些工作我们创建了一个内存泄漏
could crash the system right so this is
可能导致系统崩溃的权利 ，所以 这 是
an error so what are we going to do
错误那么，我们该怎么办
about this well it turns out that
关于这口井事实证明 ，
exceptional control flow will help us
异常控制流将帮助我们
solve this problem and what happens is
解决这个问题 ， 什么情况是
that the kernel will notify the shell
内核将通知 壳
when when a any of its children
当，当其所有子
terminate okay and then the shell can
终止 还好然后壳 可
can then react to that and issue a wait
然后可以反应到并发出等待
pit okay and this notification that
坑没关系 ，这通知
mechanism that the the kernel uses is
该内核使用机制
something called a signal so a signal is
一种叫做的信号，因此信号
a small message that the kernel delivers
一个小消息 ，内核提供
to a process to notify it that there's
到进程通知它有
been some event in the system now so
有了一些事件在系统中现在这样
this is very similar to the exceptions
这是非常相似的例外
that we studied the last time right
我们研究的最后一次正确的
except it's it's all implemented in
除了它的它在所有实施
software now kernel signals are always
现在的软件内核信号总是
sent from the kernel but sometimes
从内核发送，但有时
they're sent at the request of another
他们在别人 的请求而发送
process right sometimes the the kernel
过程有时候也是对的内核
will notice that there's some event
会发现，有一些事件
other times another process will ask the
其他时间另一个进程会问
kernel to send a message to some other
内核将消息发送给其他一些
process now that we say that it's a
现在的过程，我们说这是一个
small message because the only
小消息， 因为只有
information that's contained in a signal
即包含在一信号信息
is it it's a unique integer ID and the
是它是一个独特的整数ID 和
fact that it was it was it was delivery
事实上， 这是它是交付
okay so that's so there's nothing else
好了 ，所以这是如此没有什么 别的
in a signal except except that it
在一个信号，除了不同之处在于它
arrived and that it has some some some
赶到， 它 具有一定的某些部分
unique ID now examples of these are the
唯一ID现在的这些实施例的
sig int so signals have this like this
SIG诠释这样的信号有这种类似这样的
unique ID and then they also have a name
唯一的ID，然后他们也有一个名字
so the cig antis is what the when you
所以持反对意见的CIG是什么，当你
type ctrl C at on the command line
在命令行上输入CTRLÇ
the colonel sends us again to every any
上校再次向我们 所有的任何
processes in the foreground and the
在前景和过程
default action of receiving a SIGINT is
接收 信号情报 的默认动作是
to terminate right so this is how you're
终止权 ，所以这是 你 如何 是
running a foreground job you hit control
运行 你打控制 一个前台作业
C you get the prompt back because it
c您得到及时回来，因为它
kills that job sig kill number nine can
杀死作业SIG杀 九位 数字 可以
be used to kill terminate any program so
被用来杀死终止任何程序 ，所以
these two have sig ant and sig kill have
这两个有SIG蚂蚁和SIG有杀
the same effect on the programs me that
在节目我说同样的效果
they kill the program the the unique
他们杀了该程序的独特
aspect of sig kill is that there's no
SIG杀的方面是，有没有
way to ignore it or override it okay so
办法忽略或覆盖它好了，
this is like the failsafe as we'll see
这就像故障保护 ，我们会看到
there are there are ways to to catch and
有没有办法 赶上和
ignore other signals like SIGINT zigzag
忽略其它信号等信号情报之字形
v is the our favorite sake fault
v是我们 最喜欢 的 缘故故障
segmentation violation so if you if you
段违规所以如果你，如果你
access a region of memory that's
访问的内存，这是一个区域
protected or or not legal then your
保护或是否合法，然后你
program will the colonel will send your
程序会上校将发送您的
that process of SIG's egg V okay signal
SIG的鸡蛋V还好 信号的这一过程
and the default the default effective of
和默认的 缺省 有效 的
that is to terminate the program a sig
这是终止程序 的签名
alarm is a way within your program you
报警是你的 程序 中的方式 ，你
can arrange for a signal to be sent to
可以安排一个信号被 发送 到
yourself so you can say inside your
自己，这样你可以说你里面
program send me a sig alarm signal in
程序给我一个 SIG报警信号
three seconds something like that so
3秒 类似 的东西 ，所以
this is a way to do things like you can
这 是一种方式 做这样的事情，你可以
set up timers you can set up timeouts
设置定时器可以设置超时
like if you want to exit if you want to
就像如果你想退出，如果你 想
set a timeout value and you're doing
设置超时值和你正在做的
some some some work and you want to
一些一些一些工作，你想
guard against that that work taking
针对这项工作回吐后卫
exceptionally long time you can you can
你特别长的时间，你可以可以
you can use sig alarm to set a timeout
您可以使用 签名的报警设置超时
and then a very important one is as
然后很重要的一条是
we'll see that will be very important
我们将看到，这将 是 非常重要的
for our shell is the sig child signal
我们的 shell是 SIG孩子信号
which the colonel sends to a parent
其中上校发送到父
every time one of its children
每它的一个子时间
terminates or stops
终止或停止
okay so this is we'll see now it will
好了，所以这就是我们现在会看到它 会
fit we'll see this is how we're going
适合，我们会看到这 是我们要如何
this is how our shell that is going to
这 是 我们的外壳， 如何去
actually reap it it's all of its
实际上收割 这是其所有
children right it's by taking advantage
儿童右它是通过利用
of the cig child signal but before I can
在CIG 孩子信号 ， 但之前，我可以
show you that we need to go through a
告诉你 ，我们 需要经过一个
number of concepts around signals okay
概念数周围信号好吗
like I said the the semantics of signals
就像我说 的信号 的 语义
it's probably one of the thorniest
它可能是 最棘手的 一个
aspects of Linux it was it was developed
Linux的方面是它被开发
very early in the the lifespan of Linux
在 Linux 中的寿命很早就
when and it maybe wasn't as clean as it
当它也许不 干净，因为 它
could be right so in order to get a
可能是对的所以为了 得到
handle on signals we're going to be very
处理上我们会非常的信号
careful about defining terms and very
小心 定义术语 ，非常
careful about the way we talk about them
小心我们谈论他们的方式
so we say that the kernel sends or
所以我们说 ， 内核发送或
delivers a signal to some destination
的信号传送到一些目的地
process and it does this by setting some
的过程，它通过设置一些做这个
state in the context of the destination
状态在目的地的上下文
process now nothing happens except that
流程现在什么也没有发生，除了
some bits get changed in the destination
一些位都在改变 目的地
process context okay there's no there's
进程上下文还好有没有有
no impact of immediate impact of sending
没有发送立杆见影的影响
a signal now a kernel sends a signal
一个信号，现在一个内核发送信号
either because it detected some event in
可能是因为它检测到某些事件
the system like that like a child
该系统像 像个孩子
process is terminated for example or
过程终止例如或
another process it has asked the kernel
另一个进程，已要求内核
to send to deliver a process on a signal
要发送到的信号传递过程
on its behalf and there's a number of
代表其 并有多项
ways to do that one of them is with the
如何 做到 这一点 他们 中的 一个 是与
kill system call it's kind of an
杀死 系统调用它的种类的
unfortunate tournament it's I mean the
不幸的比赛是我 的 意思 是
so kill is a general way to send signals
所以杀是发送信号的一般方法
and the the impact is not it is
而影响不是它
sometimes not to kill the program right
有时不杀程序权
but for some reason they chose to to
但出于某种原因，他们选择了到
call it kill
把它杀
now the destination process receives a
现在目的地进程接收到一个
signal when it's forced by the kernel to
当它的内核被迫信号
act in some way to react in some way to
以某种方式行动以某种方式作出反应
the delivery of the signal okay so these
该信号的 传送 好了，所以这些
are two very different things sending a
是两个完全不同的东西发送
signal sets state in the context of the
信号中的情况下 设置 状态
destination process receiving a signal
目的地处理接收信号
is what happens when the destination
是发生在当目标是什么
process is finally forced by the kernel
过程终于迫使内核
to act in some way to react in some way
以某种方式行事以某种方式作出反应
now some possible ways to react are to
现在一些可能的 方式 做出反应是
just ignore the signal okay to terminate
只是忽略信号好吗 终止
the process or to catch the signal by
本方法或用捕捉信号
executing a user level function called a
执行用户级功能称为
signal handler so in this case when we
信号处理程序 ，以便在这种情况下，当我们
when we catch signals it's very similar
当 我们捉的信号 是非常相似
to the the and executes a signal handle
到 的，并且执行信号处理
it's very similar to executing a an
这是非常相似执行的
exception handler in response to some
在回应一些异常处理程序
kind of event in the system now the
样的系统事件的现
difference is that exception handlers
不同的是 ，异常处理程序
are in the kernel signal handlers are
在内核信号处理程序
actually just in your C code okay there
实际上只是在你的C代码 还好吧
and they execute in your in your process
他们在你在你的进程中执行
so the so the way to think about if if
所以这样的方法 来思考 ，如果如果
we catch a signal by executing a signal
我们通过执行信号搭上信号
handler we have our process executing
处理程序，我们有我们的流程执行
instructions and then the signal is
指令，然后该信号是
received by that process so the kernel
通过 这个 过程 获得 如此内核
passes control to a signal handler which
控制传递到信号处理程序 ，其
is also just in the code that's
也只有 在 这 代码
executing in the current process it's
在目前的进程是执行
just a function in our in our C code the
只是在我们在我们的C代码功能
signal handler runs and when it returns
信号处理程序运行，当它返回
it eventually returns back to the next
它最终返回到 下一个
instruction and then and we continue
指令，然后 ，我们将继续
okay so it's just like kind of like an
好了，这就像 有点像 一个
interrupt right we just temporarily
中断的权利，我们只是暂时
pause what we're doing in the in our
暂停我们在做什么我们
code to execute this this handler before
代码之前 执行 该此处理程序
just continuing on
只是在继续
okay now we say that a signal is pending
现在没事了，我们说的信号挂起
if it's been sent by the colonel but not
如果它已经被 上校，但不 发送
you have received so if at any given
你已经收到 ， 所以 如果在任何给定
point in time that can only be one
在时间点 只能是一个
pending signal of any particular type
任何特定类型的挂起信号
okay so this has very important
好了，所以这 具有非常重要的
consequences for using signals because
使用的信号，因为后果
you can't cue signals up right at any
你不能在任何提示信号右上
point in time there's there can only be
在时间点有只能有
one pending sig child signal for example
例如一个未决SIG子 信号
or six against signal and if a
或 六对信号 ，并且如果
subsequent sig child signals say is sent
随后SIG孩子说信号发送
it just over writes well you can think
它只是在写得很好，你能想到的
of it as it has no impact
它的，因为它没有任何影响
it's just discarded right if there's
它只是丢弃的权利，如果有
already a pending signal so they don't
已经挂起的信号，使他们不
they don't queue up in any meaningful
他们不以任何有意义的排队
way now our process can block the
现在这样我们的工艺可以阻止
receipt of certain signals okay now it
收到一定的信号现在没事了它
can't stop signals from being delivered
不能停止投放信号
but it can stop it can stop the process
但它可以阻止它可以停止 进程
from having to react to those to that
从具有向这些 到该反应
signal when it's received okay
当它接收到的 信号 好
so block signals can be delivered but
所以块信号可以被递送但
they won't be received until the signals
他们将无法接收到的信号
unblocked
畅通
and pending signals are received at most
和待处理的信号在接收最
once now the colonel keeps track of the
一旦现在上校跟踪的
pending and blocked signals in bit
未决且在比特阻塞信号
vectors that will call pending and
将调用挂起的载体和
blocked and pending represent the set of
阻塞和未决代表所述一组
pending signals right where each bit in
挂起信号右其中每个位
the pending bits vector corresponds to
挂起的比特向量对应于
some particular signal okay so this is
一些特定的信号好，所以这是
why they can't be cued right because
为什么他们不能正确的，因为线索
there's only one bit for any signal Kay
只有一个对任何信号 凯位
there's only one bit in the bit vector
只有一个在位 向量 位
and if we and when we deliver a signal
如果我们，当我们提供一个信号
we're just setting we'll set that bit
我们只是设置，我们将设置该 位
the colonel will set that bit we deliver
上校将设置位我们提供
another signal of the same type it'll
同类型的另一个信号， 它会
just set that bit again which has no as
只需设置该位 再次它没有 作为
no effect
没有效果
now the colonel sets that the bit in
现在上校设置该位
pending when the signals delivered and
未决 当 信号传递和
it clears it when the signals received
它清除它接收到的信号时
and the colonel also provides mechanism
和上校还提供机构
for users to block signals with this
为用户阻止与此信号
blocked bit vector so the block bit
阻止比特向量所以块位
vector is the same size as the pending
矢量的大小与待处理同
bit vector turns out it's just a 32 bit
位向量原来它只是一个32位
int okay and it can be set and cleared
诠释好，它可以设置和清除
the bits and that can be set and cleared
该位， 可设置和清除
using the sig proc mask system call okay
使用SIG PROC面罩系统调用 好吗
now there's the blocked in the Linux
现在有阻塞在Linux
literature the blocked bit vector is
文献阻塞位向量是
also called the signal mask
也称为信号掩模
okay now we're going to look in a little
好吧，现在我们要在一点点看
more detail about sending and receiving
有关发送和接收更详细
signal so let's start first with sending
信号，从而让我们先开始发送
signals first we need to understand the
信号首先我们需要 了解
idea of a process group so every process
进程组所以每一个过程的想法
belongs to exactly one process group and
属于一个进程组和
those so here I'm showing a shell that's
那些所以这里我展示一个shell这是
in process it has a process ID of ten
在过程中 它具有 10 的过程ID
and a process group ID of ten the shell
和10 的外壳 的工序组ID
created a foreground job which has a
创建具有一个前台作业
process ID of twenty and a process group
二十进程ID 和处理组
ID of twenty and then all of the
二十ID，然后所有的
children that this foreground job
孩子，这个前台作业
created have the same process group ID
创建具有相同的处理组ID
of twenty so these these process groups
20个所以这些这些过程组
can be set by a system call set called
可以通过一个名为系统调用集设置
the set process group ID and you can and
一组进程组ID，并可以中和
you can fetch that process group using
您可以 通过获取该进程组
the get process group system call so you
在获取进程组的系统调用，所以你
can see in this example what what the
在这个例子中看到什么
shell is done is it created a foreground
外壳做的是它开创了前景
child so it created this child and it
孩子所以它创造了这个孩子 ，并
changed the process group ID to be equal
改变进程组ID为等于
to the process ID of the child and then
孩子的进程ID，然后
when this child created other child
当这个孩子创建的其他子
children they just inherited the same
孩子们，他们只是继承了相同的
process group ID okay
处理组ID 没关系
now this this notion of a process group
现在这个这个概念的过程组
is useful because it allows you to send
是有用的，因为它 允许你 发送
signals to groups of processes at the
信号，以在 所述 的处理组
same time and you can do that with a
同时，你可以做到这一点 与
program called kill which is typically
称为杀程序，其典型地是
in /bin directory
在/ bin目录
and that the kill program you can use
而杀程序，你可以使用
the kill program to send an arbitrary
杀程序发送任意
signal to either an individual process
信号可以是个人过程
or all the processes in one process
或全部在一个过程中的处理
group so let's look at an example this
组让我们来看一个例子 这
program this Forks program creates two
该方案计划福克斯创建两个
children and with each of which has the
儿童和每 一个有
process group of 24 eight one seven and
的 24八一七 处理组 和
of course they have different process
当然，他们有不同的过程
they have different process IDs and so
他们有不同的进程ID等
if we if we do a PS we see these two we
如果我们如果我们做一个PS，我们看到这两个我们
see these two processes running and
看到这两个进程运行，
these just go into loop so they'll just
这些刚进入循环，这样他们就会
they'll just run continuously okay now
他们将刚才连续运行 好吗
we can come we can use kill to kill an
我们可以来我们可以使用杀 来 杀去 的
individual process for example so if we
例如个别过程，所以如果我们
call it that the first argument
把它的第一个 参数
indicates what signal you want to send
指示信号要送什么
so in this case it's its signal nine
所以在这种情况下，它的信号9
which is the cig kill signal so kill
这是CIG kill信号 所以杀
minus nine is is a very typical usually
零下 九级是一个非常典型的，通常
if you want to kill processes you just
如果你只想杀了你的过程
kill minus nine and actually one of my
杀零下九实际上我一个
favorite otto lab Mik names for 213 was
最喜欢的 奥托实验室Mik的名字 213
the nickname was killed - 915 - 1 3 so
绰号被打死 - 915 - 1 3等等
but then then the second argument is the
但随后则第二个参数是
if it's is the the process ID so this is
如果它是进程 ID，所以这是
asking this is asking the kernel to kill
问这是请求内核杀
process ID - for a 1 8 by sending it a
进程ID  - 对于1 8通过发送一个
cig kill signal now if the if the
CIG kill 信号，现在如果要是
process ID is is preceded by a - then it
进程ID是由前面-那么它
sends a signal to every process in
将信号发送到每一个过程
process group - then it treats this
进程组 - 然后把这个
argument as a process
参数作为一个过程
and it sends a signal to every process
并将其发送 信号到每一个过程
in that process group so in this case it
在这一 过程中组，以便在这种情况下，它
will send a signal to both of these both
将发出一个信号，这两个都
of these children processes and then
这些孩子的过程，然后
afterwards we if we do a PS we see that
事后我们，如果我们做一个PS我们看到，
those processes are gone okay that it
这些过程 都消失了 还好，它
really did work that way
确实工作方式
now another way to send signals is by
现在另一种方式来发送信号是
typing either control C or control Z at
打字 或者控制C或控制 ž在
the to the command line control C causes
该命令行 控制C使
the kernel to send a signal to every job
内核的信号发送到每一项工作
in the foreground process group and
前台进程组 中 和
control Z causes it to send a signal
控制ž 导致它 发送一个信号
signal to every job in the in the
信号到每一项工作中的
foreground process group the default
前台进程组默认
action for SIGINT is to terminate the
对于 SIGINT行动是终止
process the default action for the cig T
处理该 CIG T 中的默认 操作
stop is to suspend the process stop it
站暂停过程中停止
until it receives a sig CRT signal
直到它接收到SIG CRT信号
so you could see an example of this here
所以你 可以 在这里 看到 这样的 一个例子
we have a program that creates a parent
我们必须创建 一个父一个程序
and a child running in the foreground so
和一个孩子在前台 运行 ，所以
the parents running in the foreground
在前台运行的父母
now when we type control Z to the
现在，当我们输入 控制Z到了
command line the shell notifies us that
命令行 外壳通知我们
it's suspended that process and if we do
它暂停该进程，如果我们这样做
a PS we can see the parent and the child
一个PS 我们可以看到父母和孩子
indeed are suspended so the PS indicates
确实悬空，从而使PS指示
that it's suspended or stopped using RT
，它的悬挂或使用 RT 停止
now next we type in the built in the
现在接下来我们在建的类型
shell built in which is F G and F G
壳内置在其中 是F G和FG
restores those those suspended jobs to
恢复那些那些悬挂作业
the foreground so after typing F G now
前台所以 现在打字FG后
we're running this our program again in
我们再次运行这个我们的程序
the foreground and then we can kill it
前台，然后 我们就可以杀死它
by typing ctrl C which which elicits a
通过键入CTRLÇ其中哪一个引起
SIGINT whose default action is to
SIGINT其默认动作是
terminate and then when we do a PS we
终止，那么当我们做一个PS我们
see that indeed that's that they're gone
看到确实就是这样，他们已离开
now that a third way that we can send
现在，第三次的方式， 我们可以发送
signals is by using the kill system call
信号是通过使用kill系统调用
so here's an example of how that works
所以这里的如何工作的一个例子
so in this in this example we're
所以在这个在这个例子中，我们
creating end children now each of which
现在创建结束孩子 的每一个
goes into an infinite loop and we're
进入一个无限循环和我们
recording this process idea of each
每个记录的过程想法
child that we create and then in it we
我们创造的孩子，然后在其中我们
go in another loop we go through and we
去另一个循环中，我们通过和我们走
we kill each of those child processes
我们自相残杀的子进程
with by using the kill function passing
通过使用所述传递函数杀
it the process ID and the signal that we
它 的 进程ID和信号，我们
want sent to that process okay and then
要发送给该进程没关系，然后
we do our due diligence and reap each
我们做我们的尽职调查 ，并获得各
one of those children that we've
那些我们所的一个孩子
terminated
终止
now this isn't strictly necessary
现在这不是 绝对必要
because we're going to exit as soon as
因为我们要尽快退出
this 412 function returns we're going to
我们要这412函数返回
exit the code so but we're just being
退出码左右，但我们只是被
you know careful here and maybe a little
你知道这里小心，也许一点点
pedantic but
迂腐但
okay now we're now let's look at how we
现在没事了我们现在让我们来看看我们 如何
process received signals now suppose
处理接收到的信号现在假设
process a is running along executing its
处理的沿执行运行其
user code and then there's a control
用户代码，然后有一个控制
passes into the kernel because of some
进入到 因为一些 内核
exception now that exception can be
除了现在的例外可能 是
either a timer going off maybe an
无论是定时去 关的可能
interrupt or it can be a trap user calls
中断，也可以是一个陷阱用户通话
a system call okay but it's always
系统调用不错，但它总是
caused that the trap into the early
引起的陷阱初成
transferring control into the kernel is
控制转移到内核
always caused by some exception so at
总是有些例外，这样在造成
this point the kernel calls its
这一点上，内核调用它的
scheduler function and it decides to to
调度功能，它决定于
do a context switch from prophet a to
从做一个先知上下文切换到
process B and it gets processed be all
过程B和它被处理的是所有
set up and right before it returns from
建立和权利之前它返回
that exception and right before it's
该异常，右 它的前
ready to pass control back to back to
准备通过控制背靠背
trust the user code and process B it
信任乙它的用户代码和过程
checks for any signals that any pending
检查任何未决的任何信号
signals okay and it does this by
信号很好，而且它通过执行此
computing a bit vector PMD so pending
计算比特向量 PMD 所以未决
non blocked which is the logical and of
非受阻这是逻辑和的
the pending bit vector and the inverse
未决位向量和逆
of the blocked bit vector okay so PMD is
被阻止的位向量的好了 ，所以 PMD是
a list of all the pending signals that
所有等待信号的列表
aren't blocked okay so these are all the
未被阻止好了，这些都是
pending signals that should be received
应该接收挂起信号
if now as tnd is all zeros then there's
如果现在为TND都是零则有
no pending signals so it just returns it
没有待处理的信号， 所以它只是返回它
passes control back it passes control
将控制传递回它 通过控制
back to process B which can continue
回到过程B，其可以继续
executing however if if PN B is nonzero
然而执行如果如果PN B是 非零
then it chooses the smallest nonzero bit
然后选择最小的非零位
in PN B and it forces process P to
在PN B和它迫使过程p来
receive that signal the corresponding
接收相应的该信号
signal
信号
the receipt of the signal triggers some
收到信号的触发 一些
action in in the process and then we
在过程，然后我们的行动
repeat that for all the nonzero signals
重复所有非零 信号
K that are not zero bits that are set in
K表是 在设置 不 为零的位
PMD and finally when we've gone all
PMD 最后当我们已经走了所有
through all the non zero bits then we
通过所有非零位，然后我们
pass control to the next instruction in
控制传递给下一个指令在
in the in process P so the receipt of a
在过程p之间，这样的收据
signal always triggers some action which
信号始终 触发一些动作 ，其
is either the process terminates the
或者是该过程终止
process stops until it's restarted by a
过程停止，直到它被重新启动
sig con signal the process ignores the
SIG的CON信号的过程中忽略了
signal okay so that's there's always
信号好了，这就是总有
some predefined default action but we
一些预定义的默认操作，但我们
can modify that that default action by
可以修改由默认动作
using a function of system call called
使用 所谓的系统调用的 函数
signal okay so we can now signal is a
信号好了，所以我们现在可以信号是
little that's another sort of misleading
小那是另一形式的误导
kind of term just like killed right
一种长期形同杀权
because when we when we send a signal to
因为当我们，当我们发出一个信号，
a process we don't always want to kill
一个过程中，我们不要 总想 杀人
it and signal doesn't actually signal
它和信号实际上并不 信号
anything it just it just modifies the
任何东西，它只是它只是修改
default action associated with some
默认操作 一些 相关
signal okay so the signal function takes
信号好了，所以信号的功能需要
us a signal number and and then
我们的信号数，然后
specifies a change in the default action
指定默认操作的变化
for that signal and those default
对于信号和这些默认
actions can be either to ignore the
行动可以是 忽略
signal okay ignore signals of type
信号行无视类型的信号
signal revert to the default behavior
信号还原为默认 行为
for that signal or we can we can give it
该信号，或者我们可以我们可以给它
or it could be the address of a user
或者它可能是 一个用户的地址
level signal handler which is a function
电平的信号处理程序 ，其是一个函数
that we've declared in our C program
我们在我们的C程序已经声明
okay it's there's nothing special about
还好这没有什么特别的是关于
the function it has a certain prototype
该功能具有一定的原型
it has it takes a single argument which
它具有它需要一个唯一参数 ，
is the signal number so when that
是信号编号，以便当
function gets called in
函数被 调用
lots to receiving a signal that argument
手至接收 信号 这样的 说法
will be set to the signal number so
将被设置为 所述 信号数量，以便
calling signal with a and specifying a
调用带有信号和指定
signal handler is called installing a
信号处理程序被调用安装
handler and then executing the handlers
处理程序， 然后执行处理程序
referred to as catching or executing
称为捕获或执行
they are handling the signal and and
他们正在处理的信号，并与
this handle event is just like an
这种处理事件就像一个
exception handler when it when it
异常处理程序，当它时，它
returns it will be when it's executed it
返回时，它的运行它，它会
will interrupt the whatever is currently
将中断当前无论是
executing in the process when it returns
在 处理 执行 时，它返回
it will return back to that point and
它会返回 到这 一点，并
continue executing ok so here's a simple
继续执行好了，所以这里有一个简单的
example of installing a handler so here
例如所以这里安装一个处理程序
in Maine where we're going to install a
在缅因州我们要去的地方安装一个
sig int handler which is called sig int
这就是所谓的签名INT SIG INT处理器
underscore handler which is defined up
强调其定义了处理程序
here and the prototype for this function
这里的原型 这一 功能
is returns nothing and it takes a single
是什么回报，它需要一个单一的
integer argument which is the signal
整数参数 是 信号
number and returns nothing ok and after
号，并且 没有 返回 OK后
we install that handler then we're going
我们安装的处理程序，然后我们要去
to execute the pause this call which
执行暂停该调用 哪个
just waits for a signal handler to
只是等待一个信号处理程序
execute ok so pause terminates the
执行确定，所以暂停终止
current or suspense the current process
电流或悬念当前 进程
until a signal is received and a handler
直到的信号被接收和处理程序
executes in that process and then pause
执行该过程，然后暂停
then pause returns so we're going to
然后暂停了回报，我们要
wait until the SIGINT happens so sig
等到 SIGINT 发生如此SIG
entry call is when we type control C so
入口调用是当我们输入控件C等等
when you were doing your bombs did did
当你在做 你的 炸弹并没有
you panic at some point and try to hit
你恐慌在某些时候和尝试打
ctrl C to get out of it ok so that
按Ctrl C退出的就OK了， 这样
snarky message you got that was we did
令人感到讽刺的消息，你有，这是我们做
that by by installing a signal house
通过通过安装信号 房子
SIGINT handler in in your bomb ok so
在您的炸弹确定，所以SIGINT处理程序
when when you type control C that
当，当你键入控件C 是
elicits a SIGINT when that SIGINT is
，诱发SIGINT时SIGINT是
received we printed this message and
接收我们印刷此消息，并
then eventually
然后最终
let you exit now signaler signals are
让你现在退出信号机信号
another examples of concurrency now
现在并发的另一个例子
we've seen concurrency earlier in the
我们前面在看到并发
form of processes right concurrent flows
的过程右并发流形式
overlapping in time okay logical flows
在时间上重叠 没关系逻辑流
overlapping in time by definition are
通过定义在时间重叠的
concurrent now with with processes the
与进程并发现在
because they have separate address
因为他们有不同的地址
spaces those concurrent flows never
空间的并发流永远
interfere with each other right so in
彼此右 所以在干扰
some sense prophecies are very easy to
从某种意义上说预言是很容易
deal with and we don't really have to
对付我们真的没有 来
worry about being interfered with by
担心与 被 干扰
another process in fact you have to go
其实你必须 去另一个进程
to great lengths to share like to share
以很大的篇幅来分享喜欢分享
things between processes you have to use
流程之间的事情，你必须使用
specific system calls in order to say
具体的系统调用，以说
share memories between two processes now
现在两个进程之间共享内存
signals are another form of concurrency
信号是 并发的另一种形式
this is the second time this class that
这是第二次类
that you've experienced concurrency and
你所经历的并发性和
so a signal is just a concurrent flow
所以一个信号只是一个并流
it's just a logical flow a sick so a
它只是一个逻辑流程生病所以
handler is just another logical flow
处理器只不过是另一种逻辑流
that runs concurrently with your program
与程序同时运行
right so we're let's say we're executing
右所以我们假设我们正在执行
a while loop and process a okay that
while循环和处理好这
while loop is is executing and then
while循环正在执行，然后
process a receives a signal which causes
处理的接收引起的信号
a transfer of control to this handler
控制转移 给该处理程序
this handler executes so this is a
这个处理程序执行，所以这是一个
concurrent flow that overlaps in time
在时间上重叠并流
with the while loop in process a
在处理的 while 循环
eventually this handler returns and we
最终这个处理器返回，我们
return to the backtick to back to
回到 反引号要回
process a now one of the reasons signals
处理现在的 原因信号 中的一个
are so tricky is because of this this
如此棘手的是因为 这个 这个
overlapping concurrent flow
重叠并流
this concurrency because the signal
此并发性，因为信号
handler runs in the same process as the
处理程序在同一个进程中运行
main program so it shares all the global
主要程序，使这股 所有全局
variables of that program okay so you're
该方案的变量 好了，所以你
that signal handler is a function that
该信号处理程序是一个函数，它
you've declared and it has access to all
你已经声明，它具有 所有访问
all the state all the global state in
所有国家所有的全局状态
the program okay and the existence of
该方案很好，而且存在
this shared global state can create real
这个共享的全局状态可以创造真正的
problems
问题
and we'll get into more details about
我们将进入更多 细节
some of those problems so another way to
其中的一些问题，所以另一种方式
look at these signal handlers disking as
看看 这些信号处理 为碟形
concurrent flows is using this this
并发流使用该本
context switch diagram so suppose we're
上下文切换图所以假设我们
executing in process a and now at some
在一些过程中执行，现在
point a signal is delivered to process a
点的信号被 传递到处理
now nothing happens right just just the
现在没有任何反应的权利只是刚刚
pending bit gets set in process a at
中断标志位， 获取过程中的设置
this point now at some point there's a
这一点现在在某些 时候有一个
transfer of control into the kernel and
控制转移到 内核中，
the kernel decides to do a context
内核决定做一个上下文
switch from A to B and now B gets to run
从A切换到B和现在B获得运行
for a while there's another transfer of
有一段时间的另一个转移
control to the kernel and the kernel
控制内核和内核
decides to schedule process a and now
决定安排过程中，现在
right before it returns control to
权利之前返回控制
process a it notices that the depending
过程中也注意到了这取决于
bit for this signal is set so it causes
该信号位，以便它会导致
process a to receive that signal so that
处理以接收信号， 使得
executes the handler code when the
执行处理程序代码时，
handler returns it returns for brief
处理程序返回返回短暂
briefly to the kernel which then
简单的内核，然后
transfers control back to the the next
控制转移回下一
instruction that the process is going to
该进程将 指令
execute now handlers are also tricky
现在执行的处理也非常棘手
because they can be interrupted by other
因为他们可以 通过其他中断
handlers so suppose we have our main
的处理器，这样假设我们有我们的主要
program that catches the signal S which
程序映入信号S，其
causes the transfer of control to handle
导致控制 转移 到处理
or us and then we'll handle our s did
或者我们，然后我们会处理了S做
you have a question okay well handle or
你有一个问题好处理好或
else is is is executing the
其他人在被正在执行
that the program catches a signal T
该程序捕获 一个信号T
which causes a transfer of control to
它使控制转移 给
the handler first 40 and when then when
该处理程序前 40，然后当当
that handler returns it returns to the
该处理程序返回它返回到
point to the to the - to the instruction
指向的 -给指令
and handle or else that was where it was
和处理，否则，这是它在哪里
interrupted and then handler us
中断，然后我们处理程序
continues its execution and eventually
继续执行并最终
it returns back to the the point in the
它返回到 在该点
main program where it was interrupted
被中断的地方主程序
now
现在
signals but the kernel always blocks
信号，但核心 始终块
pending signals of the type currently
当前未决的类型的信号
being handled right so a handler for a
被处理的权利这样一个处理一个
signal of type T can't be interrupted by
类型T的信号不能被中断
the receipt of another signal of that
在收到该另一信号的
same type okay can be as I showed in the
同类型的好可以为我 的 表现
previous slide it can be interrupted by
一张 幻灯片可以通过中断
a signal of another type but not by a
另一种类型的信号，但不是 由
signal of the same type so that's sort
相同类型的信号，所以这是排序
of an implicit form of of blocking but
的阻塞的隐形式的，但
there's the kernel also provides a
还有的内核还提供了
system call that allows you to
系统调用，允许你
explicitly block and unblock signals in
明确地阻断和开启信号
the form of the sig proc mask function
所述SIG PROC掩模函数的形式
and then there's an Associated so this
然后有一个关联 ，以便本
allows you to block and unblock a set of
允许您阻断和开启一组
signals and then there's some support
信号，然后有一定的支撑
functions that allow you to create those
功能，允许 您创建这些
sets so just think of these as bit
集如此只是觉得这些是位
vectors and these functions will set and
载体和这些 功能将设置和
set and reset the bits and those those
置位和复位的位和那些那些
detectors so let's see how we can use
探测器让我们看看我们如何使用
sig proc mask to temporarily block and
SIG的 PROC掩模 暂时封闭和
unblock a signal so this is going to
解锁一个信号，这是怎么回事
this is going to turn out to be very
这会变成是 非常
important for you when you working on
对你很重要，当你工作
your shells that which is your next your
你的炮弹是你的下一个你
next lab assignment okay
接下来的实验任务好吗
so what we do we'll use Zig empty set to
所以我们做什么，我们将使用 齐格空集来
create an empty mask so this is a mask
创建一个空蒙版，所以这是一个面具
with all zeros okay with with no
与所有零还好有没有
elements in the set and then we're going
集合中的元素，然后我们要去
to add a single element to this set
到一个单一的元素添加到该组
which is sig int and now we temp we have
这是SIG的int和现在 我们临时，我们有
some code that we don't want to be
一些代码，我们不希望
interrupted by receipt of sig int okay
通过接收SIG INT 没关系 的中断
so we want to temporarily block the
所以我们想 暂时阻止
receipt of SIGINT signals and we do it
收到SIGINT信号，我们做
by calling sig proc mask with the
通过调用与SIG PROC面具
command say I want to block
命令说，我想阻止
I want to block the signals that are
我想阻止的信号
spected the that are in the set
spected的 是在集
specified by mask and I will sign the so
通过屏蔽指定，我将签署使
this will become my new mask so this
这将成为我的新的面具 ，让这
this becomes the new blocked bit vector
这成为新的阻塞位向量
okay or they're not the this the new
好或者他们不是这个新
signal mask and it makes a copy of the
信号屏蔽 ，这让的副本
old one and stores it at at the address
老并将其存储在该地址
specified in the third argument so at
在第三个参数，以便在指定的
this point after we returned from sig
这点之后，我们从SIG返回
proc mask sig and signals are blocked
PROC掩模SIG和信号被阻断
and they won't be received and then we
他们不会接收，然后我们
so we can execute this code knowing that
所以我们可以执行该代码知道
we won't be interrupted by receipt of a
我们不会收据被中断
SIGINT and then we can restore the
SIGINT 然后我们就可以恢复
previous block set by using the cig set
前块通过使用CIG集设置
mask in stopper ation and passing in the
掩盖塞子通货膨胀和传入
previous mask that we that we saved up
以前的面具，我们， 我们得救了
here when we when we initially blocks
在这里，当我们的时候，我们 最初块
again
再次
okay so signals and signal handling is a
好了，所以信号和信号处理是一个
really tricky business and there's sort
真正棘手的业务，并有排序
of three things that make them so tricky
三件事情，使他们如此棘手
and kind of nasty really one is that you
和那种讨厌的真正 之一是，你
have to be very careful to write
必须非常小心 地 写
handlers that are safe okay so there's
处理程序 是安全的好了，所以有
you can write signal handlers that are
你可以编写信号处理程序
unsafe in the sense that they'll create
不安全的感觉，他们会创造
a deadlock in your program okay or you
在你的程序死锁正确的，或者你
can or you can write signal handlers
可以或者你可以写信号处理
that will they'll corrupt a global data
那会他们就会产生破坏全局数据
structure that's being modified by the
多数民众赞成由修改结构
main program so I mean imagine imagine
主程序所以我的意思是想象想象
your main programming is updating some
你的主要编程一些更新
some data structure like a linked list
一些数据结构就像一个链表
and right in the middle of updating that
而就在更新中间的那个
data structure when it's when it's no
当它的数据结构时，它的无
longer consistent the program gets
长一致的程序获取
interrupted by the receipt of a signal
通过接收的信号的中断
and if that signal handler is updating
并且如果该信号 处理程序更新
that same data structure reading that
相同的数据结构读数
structure or modifying it then it's
结构或修改那么它的
going to encounter it in an inconsistent
会遇到它不一致
state and and and you're in trouble
状态，并且和你就麻烦了
so this the fact that it's the fact that
所以这样一个事实， 这是事实，
it's easy to write signal handlers that
它很容易 编写信号处理程序
are that are unsafe is is one aspect of
是不安全的是 的 一个 方面
it makes them tough to deal with another
这让他们很难对付 另一个
aspect is they have this funny semantics
一方面 是他们有这个有趣的语义
that signals aren't cued and so if
该信号不线索 ，因此，如果
you're not if you're not really careful
你不是，如果你不小心真的
about this it's very easy to use the
这个是非常 容易使用
receipt of signals to count events and
收到的信号进行 计数和事件
you can't do that
你不能这样做
if signals were cued you could use you
如果信号是线索，你可以使用你
could use the receipt of a signal to
可以使用收到信号来
count events in the system but you can't
计数系统中的事件，但 你不能
do it because their signals aren't cued
这样做是因为 他们的信号不 线索
and then the third a third aspect of
和 然后在第三第三方面
signals which makes them tough is that
这使得他们强硬的信号是，
they're not even they're not even
他们甚至 没有 他们甚至不
portable across different versions of
可跨不同 版本的
Linux okay so if you use Solaris or some
Linux的好了，所以如果你使用Solaris或一些
form of BSD it's not necessarily the
BSD的形式，它并不一定是
signal handling semantics aren't
信号处理语义不
necessarily the same as they are in
不一定，因为它们是在同一
Linux okay so well we'll look at all
Linux的好那么 好，我们来看看所有
three of these in a little more detail
这三个在更详细一点
first we'll start with
首先，我们将与启动
writing safe handlers so let me give you
编写安全的处理程序，所以让我给你
some guidelines for how to write safe
对于如何编写 安全的一些准则
handlers and this is just a collection
处理程序和这仅仅是一个 集合
of fun this is just a collection of sort
乐趣，这只是一种 集合
of collected wisdom from from various
收集的智慧来自不同
sources but it covers a lot of aspects
来源，但它涵盖 了 很多方面的
of signal handlers so the first
信号处理程序，以便第一
guideline is to keep your handlers as
原则是， 让您的处理器为
simple as possible for example the
简单越好例如
simplest possible handle I can think of
最简单可行的处理，我能想到 的
just sets a global variable and then it
只是设置 一个全局 变量，然后将其
returns and in fact cert the CMU cert
回报而事实上证书的CMU证书
provides guidelines for sort of
提供了某种指引
compliant programs and this is the only
兼容的程序，这是唯一的
signal handler that they allow this is
信号处理程序 ，他们允许这是
the only compliant signal handler one
唯一兼容的信号处理 一个
that just sets a global variable and
只是设置一个全局变量，
then returns okay
然后返回好吗
guideline number one call only functions
指导头号只调用函数
in your handlers that are that have this
在你的处理程序，它具有此
property of a sync signal safety okay
同步信号安全性能好
and we'll look at this in a second but I
我们来看看这在第二，但 我
want to point out that printout s printf
要 指出的是，打印的printf
Malak exit functions that are very
马拉克退出功能 ，是非常
common and commonly use are not safe
常见和常用 的使用 并不安全
okay
好的
guideline number two is to always save
指导号二是始终保存
and restore error no on entry and exit
和还原错误没有在进入和退出
so you know error no is a global global
所以你知道错误是没有一个全球性的全球
variable it's set when there's whenever
变量时有每当它的设置
there's an error in a system level
有一个系统 级 的错误
function so you need to save and you
功能，所以你需要保存你
need to save and restore it on entry and
需要保存，并在进入恢复和
exit so that it doesn't get overwritten
退出， 这样 它不会被覆盖
that you're interrupted by another
你正在被另一个中断
handler
处理器
[Music]
[音乐]
okay if you're accessing any shared data
没关系，如果你所访问的任何共享数据
structures inside a signal handler that
一个信号 处理器 内部结构， 其
are also accessed by your main routine
也是由主程序访问
then you need to temporarily block
那么你需要 暂时阻止
signals while you access that data
信号，同时您访问数据
structure both in the main routine and
结构既在主例程和
your signal handler right and the reason
信号处理程序权利和理由
for this is what I described earlier if
这 就是我在前面描述 是否
your main routine is updating that
你的主要程序是更新
global data structure and then it gets
全局数据结构，然后它会
interrupted and the signal handler is
中断，且信号处理程序是
reading that data structure it's going
读取数据结构这是怎么回事
to find it in inconsistent state and bad
找到它在不一致的状态和糟糕
things will happen okay you want to be
事情发生好吗你想 成为
sure to declare your any global
一定要声明你的任何 全局
variables that are shared between signal
被信号之间共享的变量
handlers and the main routine as
处理程序和主程序为
volatile okay the volatile attribute
挥发性好挥发性属性
will prevent the compiler from putting
将防止编译器把
that that value in a register so if you
在寄存器该值 ，所以如果你
declare a global variable as volatile it
声明一个 全局变量挥发性它
will always be reads and writes will
永远是 读取和写入的意志
always go to and from memory okay so
经常去，并从内存好了，
this is very important right you might
这是非常重要的权利，你可能
if you don't declare these global
如果你不声明这些全球
variables in volatile and the compiler
在易失性和编译器变量
chooses to put to put one of those in a
选择摆放其中的一个在
in a register then you may miss that
在寄存器中，那么 你可能会错过
variable being updated so suppose
变量更新因此，假设
suppose your signal handlers is setting
假设你的信号处理函数设置
a global variable and now suppose your
一个全局变量，现在假设 你
main routine is spinning waiting for
主程序在旋转等待
that global variable to get set well if
全球变量获得定好了，如果
it's in a register the write to that
它是在寄存器中写入到
variable will just update the register
变量只会 更新寄存器
right and so your main routine is in
右等你的主程序是
danger of just spinning forever not not
刚纺永远不会没有危险
seeing the change thank you
看到变化谢谢
okay so always use volatility so that
好了，所以一直使用的波动，使
they're not stored in registers and then
他们不存储在寄存器，然后
if you have fun if you have a special
如果你有乐趣，如果你有一个 特殊的
kind of global called a flag which by
一种全球性的，称为标志，该标志由
definition is a variable it's only read
定义 一个变量是只读的，
or written not incremented or updated
或书写不增加或更新
it's just read or written if you have if
它只是读或写，如果你有，如果
you have a variable with that property
你 有这个属性 变量
then you can declare it with this SIG
然后 你可以用这个SIG宣布它
atomic
原子
t attribute and if you do that then the
牛逼的属性 ，如果你这样做，那么该
system guarantees that reads and writes
系统保证了读取和 写入
to that variable be atomic so you don't
该变量 是原子的，所以你不要
have to in other words you don't have to
有换句话说，你不必
protect accesses to the shared to
保护访问到共享到
accesses or references to those global
访问或到那些全局引用
variables okay and so by this by atomic
变量好，因此使用这种由原子
what means that the the read or write of
什么意思是读或写
that flag will always happen in one
该标志总是会发生 在一个
uninterruptible step okay one
不间断一步 好一个
uninterruptible load or store particular
不间断负载或存储特定
now in practice on most systems this SIG
现在在大多数系统中，这SIG做法
atomic t is an INT kids so you can you
原子t是一个 INT孩子，所以你可以在 你
can read or write an int with one one
可以读取或 一个一个 写一个 int
instruction okay so it's it's atomic but
指令好吧，这是它的原子，但
if you want to be portable you declare
如果你想成为便携式声明
it with sig atomic t and then it will
它与 康原子 吨，然后 它会
it'll work on none it will work on all
它会在没有它的工作在所有工作
systems okay we mentioned this property
还好我们提到的这个产权制度
of async signal safety now a function is
异步信号安全的，现在的功能是
is safe to be used inside of a signal
是安全的信号的内 使用
handler if it's either reentrant okay or
处理程序如果它要么 折返 正确的，或者
if it can't be interrupted by signals
如果它不能被信号中断
and what a reentrant function is we'll
那叫一个折返功能，我们将
see when we study threads is a function
看到，当我们学习 线程是一个功能
where all of its all of the data that it
所有数据的其所有它
accesses is on its own stack okay so no
访问是在其自己的堆栈好了，所以没有
global variables no pointers to global
全局变量没有指针指向全球
variables everything's stored on the
变量的一切都存储在
stack locally okay so that means you can
本地堆放好了，这意味着你可以
be it's called reentrant because you can
可这就是所谓的折返，因为你可以
write have multiple instances of that
写有 多个实例
function and they all have their own
功能，他们都有自己的
separate copies of all of the variables
所有变量的单独副本
that they're they're using now the POSIX
他们是他们使用现在 POSIX
standard guarantees 117 different
标准保证117不同
functions to be a sync signal safe
函数是一个同步信号安全
these include underscore exit right wait
这包括强调出口权等待
wait could sleep killed but
等待 可以睡杀，但
unfortunately there's some very popular
不幸的是有一些很受欢迎
functions that aren't on this list
不在这个名单上的功能
printf s printf things that you really
的printf 的printf的东西，你真的
want to use and in fact right is the
要使用，其实正确的是
only output function that's a sync
只有输出 功能，这是一个同步
signal safe
信号安全
so this is kind of a problem because
所以这是怎样的一个问题，因为
especially when you know you something
尤其是当你知道你的东西
you'd often like your signal handlers to
你经常喜欢你的信号处理程序
output information but you can't if you
输出信息，但你不能，如果你
want to really be pedantic and careful
想要真正成为迂腐和小心
you can't use printf in fact it's
你不能在实际上用printf 它的
possible to write a program and I'll try
可以编写一个程序，我会尽力
to I'll try to it's possible to write a
到我会尝试有可能 写
program that does a tight loop of
程序， 它的一个紧密循环
printouts in the main routine and then a
在主程序中，然后 打印输出
steady stream of interrupts which
中断的稳定流，其
executes a handler which also does a
执行的处理程序也做了
printf okay now the printf call has to
printf的还好现在的printf调用具有
acquire what's called a lock on the
获得了所谓的锁
terminal okay each printf inside that
内部的终端没关系每个 printf的
that library function it acquires a lock
该库函数它获得锁
which means only one instance of printf
这意味着printf的只有一个实例
can write to the terminal in a point in
可以写入终端在一个点
time if another if another function
时间如果另一个如果另一个功能
tries to acquire that lock it has to
尝试获取锁定它有
wait until whatever function owns the
等到一切功能拥有
lock releases it okay so a lock prevents
锁定释放它好了，一个锁可防止
a lock is a way for to get mutually
锁是得到相互的方式
exclusive access to two shared resources
独家获得两个共享资源
so if we have a tight loop in our main
所以，如果我们有我们的主要紧密循环
routine with executing printf imagine
程序与执行printf的想象
what happens if one of those printouts
会发生什么，如果这些打印的一个
acquires the lock on the terminal and
获取终端上的锁定 和
then gets interrupted not by the receipt
然后获取由收据不中断
of a signal now within the signal
信号中现在 的信号的
handler it calls another printf and that
处理它调用另一个printf和那
printf tries to acquire that lock and it
printf的尝试获取锁，它
blocks forever because nothing is going
块永远因为没有任何事情
to release that lock because the the
以释放 锁，因为在
main routine was interrupted by the
主程序被中断
handler so you have what's called a
处理器让你拥有什么叫做
classical a classical condition called
古典称为经典条件
deadlock which is we have a process
僵局是，我们有一个过程
waiting for an event that will never
等待事件永远不会
occur in this case the the printf and
发生在这种情况下，printf 和
the signal handler is waiting for a lock
信号处理程序正在等待锁
to be released that will never be
被释放，这将永远是
released
发布
so it's interesting you can try this
所以这很有趣，你可以试试 这个
it's it's not too hard to to create this
这是它不是太难创建此
deadlock situation so to deal with this
死锁情况如此处理这
I really didn't want to tell you guys
我真的不想告诉你们
that you couldn't have any output in
你不能有任何输出
your programs and writes a very
您的程序和写一个 很
difficult thing to deal with so so I
困难的事情处理这么让我
created a small little library called
创建了一个名为小小图书馆
the safe i/o library consists of three
安全 I / O库包括三个
routines and they're available to you in
例程和他们是提供给您
the CSA PTC file which is distributed on
这是 分布在 CSA PTC文件
the website
网站
it consists of three reentrant routines
它包括三个折返程序
SiO put s prince/princess string put L
二氧化硅 放王子/公主串把大号
prints along and SiO error prints a
沿打印和 SiO错误 打印
message and then exits okay so you can
消息，然后退出 好了，你可以
safely use take my word for it you can
安全使用需要我的话 ，你可以
safely use this in your in your signal
安全在 你在你的信号 使用
handlers so if we were going to rewrite
处理器，所以如果我们要改写
our SIGINT handler from the from the
我们从从SIGINT处理程序
binary bomb we could rewrite it like
二进制炸弹，我们可以把 它像
this and now we have every function is
这一点， 现在我们有充分的功能
is a sync signal safe all right now
是一个同步信号安全现在好了
singles are also tough because of this
单打， 因为 这也强悍
funky non queuing semantics of and so
和这样 时髦的非 排队语义
it's really easy to make mistakes
它真的很容易犯错误
when you have an implicit assumption
当你有一个隐含的假设
that the that the receipt of a signal it
该该收到信号就
can be used to count the occurrence of
可以用于计数 的发生
an event so let's look at this let's
事件让我们 看看这个让我们
look at this example program we install
看看我们安装这个示例程序
a sick child handler okay and this is
一个生病的孩子处理好，这是
actually this sir I want to close the
其实 这个 先生，我想关闭
loop member we talked about our example
环成员，我们谈到了我们的例子中
shell we're wondering how are we going
外壳我们想知道我们如何去
to reap those those background children
收获的那些背景的孩子
well we do it by installing a sick child
以及我们通过安装一个生病的孩子做
handle like we're doing in this example
处理这样我们在这个例子中正在做
so this here we have a program that
所以这次我们在这里有一个程序，
installs this SIG child handler
安装此 SIG 孩子处理程序
and then it creates n different child
然后它创建 N个不同的 子
processes where each child sleeps for a
每个孩子睡觉的过程
little bit and exits and then it spins
点点退出，然后将其旋转
until the C count variable becomes zero
，直至C计数变量变为零
that the parent I'm sorry the parent
父对不起父
spins until the C count variable becomes
旋转，直至C 计数变量变得
zero now in the in our child handler we
现在零在我们的孩子 ，我们 的处理程序
we have a global that's that's
我们有一个全球性就是这样的
initialized to zero see count and then
初始化为零 见计数，然后
we wait we're going to wait so this
我们等待我们要等到所以这
child when the child handler gets called
孩子，当孩子处理程序被调用
that means it's called because we
这意味着这就是所谓的，因为 我们
received a sick child signal okay so in
收到一个生病的孩子信号好了，所以在
our in our handler we're going to reap
我们在 我们的处理程序，我们要收获
that child by calling weight and we're
那个孩子 通过 调用 重量和我们
going to Dec and then will decrement C
要减速，然后将递减Ç
count okay so once all of the children
算好了，一旦 所有的孩子
at then done have been reaped C count
在随后进行 已 收获 Ç 数
will be zero and then the parent can
将为零 ，然后家长可以
exit this this while loop okay now in
还好现在退出此这个while循环
this particular example n was 5 but will
这个特定的 实例中，n为 5，但将
you run this code we only the handle or
运行这段代码 ，我们只能把手 或
only gets called twice okay so the the
只有被调用两次还行，因此在
message handle or each child only gets
消息句柄或每个孩子只 得到
executed twice right which means the
执行两次右 这 意味着
handler was only called twice we created
处理程序只叫了两声 ，我们创建了
five children we terminated five
五个孩子，我们终止5
children but we only read two okay so
孩子，但我们只读过两年好了，
that the problem is that when we the
这个问题 是，当我们 的
problem is that we assumed that the
问题是，我们假设
receipt that the that the execution of
收到了该执行
the child handler corresponded to the
孩子处理对应于
single receipt of a single signal signal
单接收到单个信号的信号
okay when when in reality these signals
好时，当在现实中这些信号
aren't cued right we had in reality
没有线索的权利，我们在现实中有
multiple sick child signals were
多生病的孩子信号是
delivered to that child which kept
传递到 孩子里面存放
overriding that
从而覆盖
bid in the pending bit sector and the
出价挂起位部门和
delivery of those signals didn't didn't
这些信号的传递没有没有
have didn't cause any reaction in the
有没有引起任何反应
process until I process was was just
过程，直到我进程只是
about ready to be rescheduled and only
有关准备改期，只
then was was the signal received
然后在接收到的信号
but even though like say three signals
但是，尽管即使是像说的三个信号
were delivered only one was received
交付只有一个接收
okay so you can't use events in this
好了，所以你不能使用这个事件
case we're using event we're using
情况下，我们使用的是我们使用事件
signals to count events which in this
信号计算在这个事件
case is the termination of a child okay
情况是孩子的终止好吗
so the receipt of a signal in this case
因此接收到的信号 在这种情况下
it only indicates that at least one
它只是表明至少有一个
child terminated right not not one child
孩子终止权不是没有一个孩子
terminated all we can infer from the
终止了所有我们可以从推断
receipt of that signal is that at least
接收到该 信号的是，至少
one child is terminated okay so to fix
一个孩子好吗因此终止修复
that when we receive a sick child we
当我们收到一个生病的孩子 ，我们
have to put we have to put the weight
必须把我们必须把重量
that's reaping on our children we have
多数民众赞成在收获我们的孩子，我们有
to put that in this in a loop so we have
把在 这一个循环，所以我们 有
to assume that the receipt of a sick
假设收到一个生病的
child if we get a sick child there could
孩子如果我们得到一个生病的孩子有可能
be multiple terminated children that we
有多个终止的孩子，我们
have to that we have to reap and so we
有，我们有收获，所以我们
put we put that in this loop and we
把我们提出，在这个循环中， 我们
execute this loop until there's no more
执行这个循环，直到有没有更多的
terminated children in which case wait
终止儿童在这种情况下 等待
will will will exit with an error code
将将将退出并返回错误代码
of minus one and a eronel of a child so
减去一个和 孩子的 eronel这样的
this isn't really an error it's just it
这是不是 真的 ，它只是它 的一个错误
just means there's no more terminated
只是意味着没有更多的终止
children so we check as long as if our
孩子，所以我们只要检查是否我们
error knows naughty child then we have
错误知道 淘气的孩子 则有
an error otherwise we terminated
一个错误，否则 我们终止
normally as we expected now if we run
通常，我们目前预计，如果我们运行
this code now we we see that we reap all
此代码现在我们大家看到 ，我们所有的收获
five children is as we should
五个孩子是我们应该
okay so look the litany of problems with
好了，所以看的 有 问题的一长串
signals first it's easy to write
第一个信号， 它可以很容易编写
handlers that aren't safe second it's
处理程序并不安全第二它的
easy to get the semantics wrong third
容易 得到语义错误的 第三
they're often not even portable across
他们 往往 跨越 是 连便携式
different Vernors versions of Unix
Unix的 不同版本Vernors
so there's some older systems I don't
所以有一些老的系统我不
know if any there's some earlier
知道任何有一些早期
versions of Unix that after you catch a
的Unix版本，你抓后
signal it restores the default action so
信号恢复到默认操作 ，以便
you have to reinstall the handler every
你必须每次重新安装处理程序
time well every time a handler gets
每一个处理程序获取时间以及时间
called you have to re-install the
叫你不得不重新安装
handler by calling signal inside the
通过调用内部信号处理程序
handle itself and we don't have to do
处理本身，我们没有做
that for for Linux systems on on some
这适用于Linux 在某些 系统 上
systems when you have so-called slow sis
当你 所谓的慢 SIS 系统
calls for example read you know if you
呼吁例如读取你知道，如果你
do a read system call the kernel doesn't
做一个读系统调用内核不
wait around for that data to arrive is
在附近等 数据到达是
it you know it sends a request to the
它，你知道它发送一个请求
disk controller and that schedules
磁盘控制器和 时间表
another process right so in a way that
另一个程序的权利等等的方式 ，
the read call is sort and then only when
读取调用进行排序，然后只有当
the data arrives and the interrupt comes
数据到达和中断到来
in announcing that the data arrives does
在宣布数据到达呢
that read call finish and then restores
该读取通话结束后恢复
and returned so you can think of read is
并 返回 所以你可以把 读的是
actually kind of broken up into two
其实那种分为两个
parts right did and so that functions
部分权没有和使功能
like read these kind of functions are
喜欢读这几 样功能
called slow sis calls and on some
所谓慢SIS通话和一些
systems if the process receives a signal
如果该过程接收的信号系统
before a slow system calls has finished
前一个缓慢的 系统调用已完成
the kernel will will just abort that
内核将只会是中止
system call in return from that system
系统调用 在 从该系统返回
call with an error okay so from user's
有错误好了，所以从 用户的呼叫
point of view you're doing a read call
的角度来看，你正在做的读取调用
and it returns with this this e enter
并将其与此此电子邮件进入返回
signal this e enter error you did
这个信号e输入错误，您做了
nothing wrong you just happen to have
没有错，你恰好有
the bad luck of being interrupted by
由被打断的厄运
some signal and so in your user code you
在用户代码中的一些信号等你
have to check for that and if if they
要检查 这一点 ，如果如果他们
slow system call like read is
慢行系统调用，比如读是
interrupted by signal you have to redo
被信号中断，你必须重做
it so you have to put which is really a
它，就必须把这实在是一个
pain right because you have to put these
疼痛正确的，因为你必须把这些
these read calls in a loop and keep keep
这些阅读在一个循环调用，并保持保持
looping until it succeeds and finally
循环，直到成功为止，最后
some systems don't block signals of the
有些系统不阻塞的信号
type being handled right so the solution
类型是正确的处理，这样 的解决方案
for this is a replacement for signal so
因为这是对于信号的替代，以便
the problem is with this signal siskel
问题是与该信号 siskel
and the solution is a newer sis called
解决的办法是叫一个较新的SIS
called Zig action which provides a
称为齐格作用，这提供了一种
mechanism a replacement for signal that
机构用于信号替换该
provides a mechanism for portable and
提供了一种机制用于便携式和
predictable signal handling and so what
可预见的信号处理等什么
I've done what I've done is created a
我所做 的就是创建了一个 我做了 什么
rapper called uppercase signal that
说唱歌手所谓的大写的信号
takes the same arguments as the signal
采用相同的参数的信号
call but inside it calls the sig action
呼叫，但里面调用签名行动
function to get portable signal handling
函数来获取便携式信号处理
and so it's it's not really important to
所以这是它 不是真的很重要
go into detail about this the point is
进入详细 介绍这一点是
in your code you always want to call
在你的代码，你 总是想打电话
uppercase signal using the rapper that
使用说唱大写信号
provided in si si PP dot C and then if
在 硅Si PP C点 提供 ，然后，如果
you do that then you'll always block
你这样做，那么你将永远 阻止
signal to the typing
信号的打字
handle the system will automatically
自动处理系统将
restart closest calls that have been
重新启动已经接近电话
interrupted by by signals okay so
中断由信号 好了，所以
fortunately there's an easy fix for this
幸好有一个简单的办法解决这个
now let's let's finish up with them
现在让我们，让我们完成了 他们
there's some interesting I mentioned
有一些有趣的，我提到
that signals are difficult because of
该信号是困难的，因为
these the fact that they're they're
这些事实 ，他们是他们
concurrent flows so I want to look at
并发流，所以我想看看
some sort of subtle issues that you can
某种微妙的问题，你可以
run into because of this concurrency and
到因为这个并发运行 ，
and I want to talk about how to identify
我想谈谈如何 识别
those errors and how to fix them
这些错误以及 如何解决 这些 问题
so here's a program that this is like a
所以这里有一个程序， 这是一个像
simple shell program that maintains a
维护一个简单的shell程序
jobs list right so every time it creates
作业列表每一次正确因此 它创建
a new child it adds it to the jobs list
一个新的孩子就其添加到任务列表中
and every time that child terminates it
而每一次当孩子终止它
removes it from the jobs list okay so so
删除它从作业列表好了，所以
our simple shell just in a loop it just
我们简单的外壳只是在一个循环中，它只是
creates a child and then executes the
创建一个子，然后执行
program within that child and then in
那个孩子中，然后在程序
the parent it correctly blocks all of
父它正确地阻止所有的
the signals temporarily while it adds a
暂时的信号，同时它增加了一个
job to the job queue and then it
作业添加到作业队列，然后将其
unblocks and then it unblocked those
放开，然后解封 那些
signals okay so this is correct and that
还好信号，所以这是正确的 ，
it's protecting access to this shared
它保护访问这个共享
job queue because that that that job
作业队列，因为这是该作业
that job queue is also manipulated by
该作业队列也被操纵
the sick child handler so when when a
病儿 的处理程序，所以当一个时
child terminates and the parent receives
终止童和家长接受
the signal this handler runs and this
该处理器运行信号，这
handler goes through and it reaps all of
处理经过，并收获所有的
the children potentially terminated
孩子们可能终止
children and then for each one it
孩子再为每 一个 它
deletes that that job from the job queue
删除从作业队列作业
all right so here's a classic case we
好吧所以这里是一个 典型的情况下，我们
have two concurrent flows our main
有两个并发流我们的主要
routine and our our signal handler
常规和我们的我们的信号处理程序
they're each accessing a shared data
他们每个访问共享数据
structure in this case the the job queue
结构在这种 情况下，作业队列
okay and they're there correctly
好吧，他们是正确的有
blocking signals while they update this
阻塞信号而他们更新这
this job queue but this program has a
这个作业队列但这个 方案有一个
really subtle and nasty bug in it
真是微妙和它讨厌的错误
can you see what it is what's the
你可以看到它是什么， 什么是
sequence of events that would cause this
事件的顺序，将导致此
program to to fail yes
程序失败是
exactly that's exactly it so is it
正是这正是它如此是它
possible that the the child process
可能是因为子进程
could terminate before the parent has a
可以终止家长有一个前
chance to add that job to the queue and
机会是作业添加到队列中 ，
the answer is yes right we you cannot
答案是肯定正确的 ，我们就可以不
make any assumptions about the execution
做出关于执行任何假设
ordering of the child in the process or
在这个过程中孩子的顺序或
about how long they run right so it's
关于他们的权利所以它的运行多久
it's very possible that the child can
它 很可能 是孩子能
connect after after the four control
四个控制后连接后
returns to the child instead of the
返回到孩子，而不是
parent and then the child terminates
父母，然后孩子终止
before the parent ever has a chance to
之前父曾经有机会
to add that job to the job queue so now
该作业添加到作业队列所以现在
what's happened is that the the child is
发生了什么事是 ，孩子
deleting a deleting a job that hasn't
删除删除具有不工作
been added to the job queue right and
被 添加到 作业队列权
now when the parent finally gets around
现在当父母终于得到周围
to running it adds that job to the job
要运行它补充说，工作就是工作
queue and that job will never be deleted
排队和作业将永远不会 被删除
so this is the kind of subtle nasty
所以这是那种微妙讨厌的
horrible kind of bug that you run into
可怕的一种错误， 你碰上
when you're dealing with concurrency
当你处理并发
trying to keep track of all of these
试图让所有的 这些 轨道
interleaving of events can just make
事件的交织可以只让
your head explode all right now and it
你的头 ，现在突然 爆炸 ，它
happens and Sigma it happens with any
发生和Sigma与任何情况
kind of concurrency where you have
一种并发的，你必须
concurrent flows accessing shared
并发流访问共享
resources and signal handlers are no
资源和信号处理程序是没有
different now we'll look at principles
现在不同了，我们来看看原则
ways where we can deal with this kind of
方式，我们可以应付这种
sharing when we study threads later on
当我们后来研究线程共享
but I just want to point this out to you
但我只是想指出 这一点你
and scare you a little bit all right so
和吓唬你一点点没事 如此
here's how we would fix that what we
这里就是我们将如何解决这个问题正是我们
have to do is somehow avoid that avoid
需要做的就是以某种方式避免避免
the to avoid the possibility of the
该避免的可能性
child handler executing before the
孩子处理程序之前执行
parent can add the corresponding job to
家长可以相应的作业添加到
the job queue now we can't control
作业队列现在我们无法控制
whether the child executes first or the
孩子是否执行第一或
parent execute first and we can't
父执行第一 ，我们不能
control how long the child runs but we
孩子的运行控制多久，但我们
can control when the big child handler
可以控制当 大孩子处理程序
runs because we can block signals
运行，因为我们可以 阻止信号
okay so what we'll do we'll modify our
好了，所以我们要做的，我们要修改我们的
program to will you sig proc mask to
节目你会SIG的 PROC 面具
block sig tiled signals before we create
块SIG 平铺信号 ，我们 之前 创建
the child okay so at this point after
孩子好了，所以在这一点后，
this invocation of sig proc sig child
这个调用SIG PROC SIG的孩子
signals are blocked okay then we create
信号好阻止后来我们创造
the child and before we do our eggs xee
孩子和我们做我们的鸡蛋XEE前
since we don't know that child may may
因为我们不知道，孩子可能将在5
need to reap its children right we don't
需要获得其子女的权利，我们不
know if it by default children inherit
知道，如果它在默认情况下 继承的孩子
the the blocked bit vector of their
的阻塞的位向量其
parents okay so when this child run F
父母好，所以当这个 孩子运行F-
after it returns from fork at this point
后从叉子在这一点上返回
right after the fork sig child is
右后 叉 SIG孩子
blocked in the child as well right so if
挡在了孩子，以及正确的，所以如果
we didn't do anything if the child
我们没有做任何事情，如果孩子
created children and try to reap you
创建儿童和尝试种瓜得
know reap them with a sick child handle
知道有一个生病的孩子 把手他们收获
that sick child handler wouldn't run
那生病的孩子处理程序将无法运行
right so that would be a problem so in
右所以这将是一个问题，所以在
the child before we execute that the
孩子之前，我们 执行的是
program itself we unblock sick child and
程序本身我们 疏通 生病的孩子和
this is an example that I was alluding
这是我被 暗指 的示例
to last time of how it's useful
于它是如何有用的最后一次
sometimes to separate creating processes
有时 以分离创建进程
with executing programs okay so this
有好的执行程序，以便本
allows us to get our our signal mask set
使我们 能够 得到我们的我们的信号 掩码 集合
up the way we want it before we run our
向上的方式，我们希望 我们运行 之前 我们
program in the child so now even if the
程序在孩子所以现在即使
child terminates early the sig child
孩子早期终止的 SIG孩子
handler won't run until after we've
处理程序将无法运行，直到我们经过
added the job to the to the job queue
添加作业到作业队列
because we don't unblock sig child until
因为我们不解除SIG的孩子，直到
after the until after we call a job okay
之后，直到后我们所说的工作好吗
okay now there's another so this this
还好现在有另一个所以这本
sort of scenario will be very relevant
那种情景将 是非常 相关的
to you when you do your shell lab okay
你当你做你的shell实验室好吗
so you want to be careful not to not to
所以你要小心， 不要 不要
make that mistake another another thing
犯 这种错误的另一个另一件事
that you you're going to need to do in
你你 将需要做的
your shell lab now you remember in our
你的shell实验室现在你 还记得 我们
simple simple shell example we did the
简单简单的shell例子，我们做了
weight inside the main routine so we
重量主程序，所以我们内部
waited for foreground jobs using weight
等待使用重量就业前景
but now in a real shell we're going to
但是现在真正的外壳，我们要
have our sick child handler do all those
有我们生病的孩子处理程序做 所有这些
all the ways call all the weights and
所有的方式调用所有的权重和
it.we so we can't put the weight has to
it.we所以我们不能把重量有
go in the cig child handler can't go in
走在CIG 孩子处理程序不能进去
the main routine okay so it so high if
主程序好了，所以这么高，如果
we can't put a weight in the main
我们不能把重量在主
routine how are we going to how are we
日常我们怎么怎么的我们
going to detect that our foreground job
去检测， 我们的前台作业
is finished
结束了
so somehow so what we could do we could
所以在某种程度上所以我们能做什么，我们能
define in the cig child handler when we
定义在 CIG孩子处理程序时，我们
read the foreground job right we've
阅读我们已在前台工作的权利
created a foreground job when we read
创建当我们读到一个前台作业
that foreground job we could set this
是前台作业 ，我们可以设置 这个
global flag we could declare the process
全局标志，我们可以申报过程
this process ID a variable PID as a
这个过程ID 的变量PID 作为
global flag and then just assign the
全局标志，然后就分配
process idea of the of the foreground
的前景的过程想法
job okay so in this is an example of a
工作好了，所以这个是一个例子
handler it just all it does it sets a
处理程序，它只是所做的只是设置一个
flag and then exits and then in our main
标志， 然后退出，然后在我们的主
routine okay we want to we want to block
常规没关系 ， 我们要 ，我们要阻止
Zig Cal just but just like before okay
齐格 卡尔只是 但 就像之前没关系
to avoid that that race condition
为了避免那场比赛状态
between the parent and the child and
家长和孩子之间
then we create the child and then and
然后我们创建了孩子 ，然后和
then in the and then the parent we set
然后在再父我们设置
PID to zero okay then we unblock Zig
PID到好 零 ，则我们解除齐格
child and then we wait for the sick
孩子，然后我们等待生病
child handler to run and set T ID to non
孩子处理程序运行，并令T ID非
zero okay okay everybody see that I mean
零还好还好大家看到 我的意思
this so this is correct right but it's
这所以这是 正确的 权利，但它是
extremely wasteful right we're spinning
极其浪费的权利，我们正在纺
we're using valuable processor cycles in
我们用宝贵的处理器周期中
this in this tight spin loop just
这在这种紧密的自旋循环刚
executing over and over and over and
执行一遍又一遍又一遍，并
over and over and over for who knows how
一遍 又一遍又一遍 对谁知道如何
long okay so that's not a good that's
长好了，这 不是一个好这
not a good solution all right so let's
没有一个很好的解决方案没事让我们
look at a couple other things we might
看看其他几件事情 ，我们可能
might consider and that have been
可以考虑与已
considered by generations of 213
通过213世代考虑
students so one thing you might think
学生这么一件事，你可能会认为
well I'll just instead of just putting a
嗯，我会只是 ，而不是仅仅把一个
semicolon here I'll pause and then I'll
分号在这里，我会停下来，然后我会
wait for the sick child handler to run
等待着生病的孩子处理程序运行
and then I'll go back up and I'll check
然后我就回去了 ，我会检查
I'll check the ID again
我会再次检查ID
now you have to put this in a loop it
现在你必须把这个循环它
still has to be in a loop because we
仍然是在 ，因为我们 一环
have other signal handlers in our
在其他信号处理程序我们
program we have a signet handler so it
节目中，我们有一个印处理程序，以便它
might be if we do the pause here and
如果我们在这里做的暂停可能是和
this again comes in and say get to get
这再次进来， 说 去获得
handler runs that would cause us to exit
处理运行时，会导致我们退出
the pause function and go back up so we
暂停功能和涨回去 ，所以我们
have to keep checking PID because we're
必须继续检查PID因为我们
not sure we have to keep checking for
不知道我们要不断检查
the specific signal handler see child
具体 的 信号处理程序 见孩子
handler to run instead of other handlers
处理程序运行，而不是其他处理
that might run but this is actually
可能运行 ，但其实这是
wrong because it has a race can you see
错误的，因为 它有一个比赛，你可以看到
what the race is
什么种族
what's wrong with this there's a good
有什么不对这个有一个很好的
chance that this thing will block
的机会，这件事情 将阻止
forever yes
永远是
yeah that's so the the problem the
是啊，这使该问题
problem with this is like so if the
这个问题是像 这样，如果
signal if the signal is received after
如果之后接收到的信号的信号
PID is checked but before the pause
PID检查，但在暂停之前
executes okay which is possible right
执行好这是可能的 权
it's unlikely but it's possible if that
这是不可能的，但它可能如果
if that signal is arrives here then the
如果信号在这里到达，则
handler will set T ID to non zero and
处理程序将组T ID为非零 和
then we'll execute the pause and the
然后我们会执行 暂停和
pause will be blocked forever waiting
暂停将永远阻塞等待
for a signal that will never arrive
对于将 永远不会到来 的信号
right because the sig Tau's signal
就是 因为这个SIG 头的信号
already already came very subtle right
已经来到了已经非常微妙权
so this code looks okay it looks benign
所以这段代码看起来 不错，它看起来 良性
but it's wrong and and and your program
但它是错误的，并和你的程序
would just hang forever so we say well
就只是挂永远所以 我们说好
okay that's no good we could replace the
还好这不是什么好，我们可以更换
pause with a sleep so we could say let's
与睡眠暂停，所以我们可以说，让我们
let's check T ID and then sleep for some
让我们来检验T ID，然后睡了一段
predetermined amount of time in this
预定在该时间 量
case one second and then go back up and
案例一秒钟，然后回去起来
check PID again so this while this is
再次检查PID所以这同时这也是
correct it's way too slow right we're
纠正它的通行权太慢我们
asking the system to wait for a second
要求系统等待第二
which is an eternity and there's there's
这是一个永恒的 和有有
forms of sleep or nanosecond where you
睡眠或 纳秒，你的形式
can wait instead of units of seconds you
可以等待，而不是单位为秒你
can wait in units of nanoseconds but
可以纳秒为单位，但等待
that what value you use right it's that
什么珍惜 你使用权它是
so that's if you choose a value that's
所以这就是，如果你选择的值 是
too large then you have this problem the
过大，那么你有这个问题的
slowness problem if you choose a sleep
如果你选择了睡眠缓慢问题
time that's too small then you have the
时间太小，那么你 有
other problem it's it's inefficient so
另一个问题是它的效率低下等等
the solution is to use sleep suspend
该解决方案是使用睡眠暂停
which is the last last thing we're going
这是我们要过去的最后一件事
to look at today so SIG's suspend is a
看今天这么 SIG的暂停是
function that takes a signal mask and
函数，它接受一个信号掩模和
it's equivalent to an uninterruptible
它相当于一个不间断
version of these three statements so we
这三个语句，所以我们的版本
block the signals that are specified in
块被指定的信号
the signal mask
信号掩码
and then it's atomic in the sense that
然后它在这个意义上是原子
after this this these two statements
这 之后， 这两个 声明
can't be interrupted they're always
不能被 打断他们总是
executed together okay so we block these
所以我们阻止这些 执行起来 好吗
signals and then we execute the pause
信号，然后我们执行暂停
okay so there's no chance of a signal
好了， 没有 信号的机会
interrupting this program in between the
在之间的干扰这个计划
sig proc mask and the pause okay and
SIG的PROC面具和暂停很好，而且
then and then when a signal does come in
然后，然后，当信号不进来
and the execution of the handle or
和手柄的执行或
causes pause to exit then we set the
原因暂停退出然后我们设置
mask back to what it was before okay so
面具回到它以前好了，
the proper way then to wait for a signal
那么正确的方式来等待一个信号
is to use sig suspend in the following
是使用SIG下面暂停
way so here's our here's our program
方式，使这里是我们这里的我们的计划
again we before we create the child we
我们 再次 之前，我们创建了 我们 的孩子
block sig child then we create the child
阻止SIG孩子那么我们创建子
and now we're going to wait for the sick
现在我们要 等待生病
child to be received now sick child is
要接收的孩子现在病儿
still blocked okay so there's no danger
还堵好，所以没有危险
of the sick child handler running okay
病儿处理好运行
so we set that global variable to zero
所以我们设置全局变量为零
and then while it's while it's non zero
然后，而它，而它的 非零
we repeatedly call sick suspend and sick
我们多次拨打 生病暂停和生病
suspend is using the previous mask that
暂停使用以前的掩码
was set up here so sick suspend is using
成立了这里，所以 生病暂停使用
the mask where sick child is unblocked
在那里生病的孩子是畅通的面具
okay when we when we entered this first
好吧，当我们，当我们进入这个第一
cig proc mask sig child was unblocked so
CIG PROC面具 SIG孩子 这么 畅通
this allows inside the sig suspend sig
这使得SIG内暂停SIG的
tiles is unblocked okay so it allows for
瓷砖畅通 好了，所以它允许
the the handler now to be received or to
在处理程序，现在要接收或
be executed okay so win it and it does
没事的执行，从而赢得它，它
it safely because of the uh the atomic
它安全， 因为 呃原子 的
nature of those those first two
那些那些前两个性质
instructions
说明
so once the so it's possible that the
所以一旦所以它可能是
implicit pause inside a sick child could
一个生病的孩子里面隐含的中断，就可能
be interrupted by say another signal
通过说另一个信号中断
like SIGINT okay in which case we'd loop
像SIGINT还好在这种情况下，我们就不断循环，
back up we'd notice that PID was still
备份，我们会发现 ，PID仍然
zero and we go back into sick suspend
零 和我们回去到 生病暂停
with with sick child unblocked okay
与生病的孩子 好吗 畅通
so that makes sense to everybody and now
这样才有意义给大家，现在
so this is exactly the behavior we want
所以这正是 我们想要的行为
where we're not wasting resources but
这里我们 不浪费资源，而且
we've eliminated the race okay so that's
我们已经消除了比赛 好了，这就是
it for today if you're interested non
好了，今天 如果你有兴趣的非
non-local jumps are this weird thing and
非本地的跳跃是 这个奇怪的事情和
see that allows a function to return to
看到允许函数返回
some other function that didn't call it
这并不能称之为一些其他的功能
but it's described in your textbook and
但它在你的 课本定律描述和
also in some additional slides here up
也正是在这里一些额外的幻灯片
here if you're interested
在这里如果你有兴趣